Guide to the Jack Censer collection, 1953-2011
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center.
- Series 1: Offprints, 1953-2010 (Boxes 1-17)
  - McMahon, Darrin, "The Counter-Enlightenment and the Low-life of Literature in Pre-Revolutionary France,", 1998 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - McMahon, Darrin review by Jack Censer, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Memphis paper, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Merrick, Jeffrey articles, 1980, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Mettam, Roger review by Jack Censer, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Meyering, Anne, "A New History of the French Revolution,", 1990 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Meyers, Peter, "Teachers in Revolutionary France: the Instituteurs in 1848,", circa 1980s-1990s (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Miles, John, "Believing in the Power of Words,", 1986 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Mitchell, Harvey, "Politics in the Service of Knowledge,", circa 1970s (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Moltke-Hansen, David, "The Paper Arm of the Courts,", circa 1980s-1990s (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Morgan, Philip, "Work and Culture,", 1982 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Moulinas excerpt from "Modeles et Moyens de la Reflexion Politique au XVIIIeme Siecle,", 1977 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Moreau, "Reflexions sur la Communication Manuscrite,", 1990s-2000s (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Munck, Thomas review by Jack Censer, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Murray, William articles, circles 1980s-1990s, 1989-1991 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Necheles, "Elitism and Republicanism in the Controversy over the French Liturgy,", circa 1970s-1980s (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Netter, "La Demande Populaire en Matiere d'Instruction Elementaire en Milieu Rural,", circa 1980s-1990s (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Newman, Edgar, "Changing Images of the Crowd in the French Revolution of 1830,", 1980s-1990s (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Newsletter of the Program in the History of the Book in American Culture, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Noakes, Susan articles, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Offen Karen articles, 1983-2000 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Offprints and printed articles, 1996-2003 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Otte, George, "Role Theory and the Judicial Process,", 1972 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - O'Brien, Patricia review, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Palmer, R.R. articles, circa 1980s-1987 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Parker, Harold T. articles, 1965-1997 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Pendleton, Gayle articles, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Peroutka, Shirley dissertation, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Perrot, Michelle, "Workers and Machines in France During the First Half of the Nineteenth Century,", 1977 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Perny, Debra, "Publishers, Politics, and the Discovery of the Popular Reader in France,", circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Pinto, Diana, "The Immigrant Question in France,", 1986 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Pocock, J.G., "The Political Economy of Burke's Analysis of the French Revolution,", 1980 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Popkin, Jeremy papers (1 of 2), 1981-2004 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Popkin, Jeremy papers (2 of 2), 1980-1993 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Press (Washington Post), 1982 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Pugh, Evelyn, "John Stuart Mill and the Women's Question in Parliament, 1865-1868,", circa 1980s (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Ramsey, Matthew, "Traditional Medicine and Medical Enlightenment:, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Redman intro to Voltaire, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Reefe, Thomas articles, 1978-1979 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Reichart, Rolf article, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Reid, Donald, "The Role of Mine Safety in the Development of Working-Class Consciousness and Organization,", 1981 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Reinhardt, Steven, "Crime and Royal Justice in Ancien Regime France,", 1983 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Resnick, Daniel, and Lauren Resnick, "The Nature of Literacy,", 1977 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Reproductions of 18th century books, 1970s (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Retat, Pierre articles (1 of 2), 1989-1996 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Retat, Pierre articles (2 of 2), 1989-1996 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Retat, Pierre letter and photocopies, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Reviews of Foucault's "History of Sexuality,", 1979-1981 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Riach, Douglas, "Blacks and Blackface on the Irish Stage, 1830-60,", circa 1980s (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Richter, Melvin, "Conceptual History (Begriffsgesichte) and Political Theory,", 1986 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Riley, James and others, articles, 1970s-1980s (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Ritvo, Harriet articles, 1981-1985 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Roche, Daniel, "Urban Reading Habits during the French Enlightenment,", circa 1970s (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Roger, Phillipe articles, 1987-1989 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Rooney, John article, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Root, Hilton articles, 1986-1991 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - de Rippe, Charles, photocopy of 19th century article, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Rose, R.B., "The 'Red' Scare of the 1790s,", 1984 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Rothkrug, Lionel lectures, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Ryan, John F., "An Analysis of the Jacobin Society,", circa 1970s (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Sampoli, Fabio, "A Popular Traditional Punishment in a Revolutionary Context,", circa 1970s (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Saugnieux, Joel, "Le Temps, l'Espace, et la Presse au Siecle des Lumieres", 1978 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Sawyer, Jeffrey article, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Schudson, Michael review by Charles Forcey, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Schulbohm, Jurgen articles, 1980-1984 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Schwoerer, Lois articles, 1986, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Scott, Joan, "French Feminists Claim the Rights of 'Man' ,", 1991 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Scott, John Anthony, Babeuf article, defense, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Sgard articles, circa 1980s (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Shaheen, David, "The French Revolutionary Settlement and Moderate Republicanism,", 1997 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Shapiro, Barry article, etc, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Shapiro, Barry articles, 1950s photocopies, 1980s-1990s (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Sheppard, Thomas, "The Clergy of Touraine at the Time of the Revolution,", circa 1980s (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Sheridan, George, "Exploitation or Abandonment,", 1977 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Shorter, Edward, "Women's Diseases before 1900,", circa 1970s-1980s (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Shulim, Joseph, "The Continuing Controversy over the Etiology of the French Revolution,", 1981-1982 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Skinner, Quentin, "Meaning and Understanding in the History of Ideas,", undated (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Smith, B article, undated (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Smith, Bonnie review by Jack Censer, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Smith-Rosenberg, Carroll, "The Female World of Love and Ritual,", undated (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Soder, John, "El Plan Americanista de Jose de San Martin,", 1978 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Sonenscher, Michael, Steven Blakemore review by Jack Censer, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Spindler, Frank, "Francisco Bilbao, Chilean Disciple of Lamennais,", 1980 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Stearns, Peter, "On Mead on American National Character,", 2001 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Stein, Robert, "The Revolution of 1789 and the Abolition of Slavery,", 1982 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Steinert, Steven and Frank Petrusak, "The Jews of Charleston,", 1976 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Stillson, Richard T., "Virginia Newspapers in the 1830s,", 1994 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Stocker, Christopher, "Judicial Reform and Renaissance Monarchy,", circa 1970s-1980s (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Stoianovich, Traian articles, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Stoianovich, Traian review by Jack Censer, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Stone, Bailey review by Jack Censer, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Stone, Bailey, "Robe against Sword,,", 1975 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Strauss, David review by Jack Censer, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Sudhir, P., "Colonialism and the Vocabularies of Dominance,", 1993 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Sullivan, Charles articles and CV, 1970s-1980s (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Sussman, George, "The Glut of Doctors in Mid-Nineteenth Century France,", 1974 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Sutherland, D.M.G., 1989-2002 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Tacket, Timothy articles, 1980s (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Taylor, George articles, 1964, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Thompson articles, circa 1990s (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Thompson, E.P., "The Moral Economy of the English Crowd in the Eighteenth Century,", 1971 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Todd, Christopher, "French Advertising in the Eighteenth Century,", 1989 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Traugott, Mark review by Jack Censer, 1986 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Trumbach, Randolph review of Lawrence Stone, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Turner, James articles, 1980-1981 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Turner, James, "Recovering the Uses of History,", 1981 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Veit, Patrice, "Le Cantique Lutherien et ses Prolongement Jusqu'a l'Epoque de J.S. Bach,", 1983 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Vincent, Steven and Kenneth Margerison, articles, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Van Dijk, Suzanna review by Jack Censer, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Van Kley, Dale, conference papers by several authors (1 of 2), 1991 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Van Kley, Dale, conference papers by several authors (2 of 2), 1991 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Van Kley, Dale, "The Jansenist Constitutional Legacy in the French Pre-revolution, 1750-1789,", circa 1970s-1980s (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Van Kley, Dale review by Jack Censer, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Vard, Liana, "Imagining the Harvest in Early Modern Europe,", 1996 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Virginia Quarterly review guidelines, circa 1970s (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Vovelle, Michel, "Le Tournant des Mentalites en France, 1750-1789,", circa 1970s (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Wade, I.O., "Philosophe in Drama of the 18th Century," 1926 article reprint, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Wade, Rex articles, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Waterhouse, Richard, "England, the Caribbean, and the Settlement of Carolina,", circa 1970s (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Weber, Eugen, "Action Francaise" outline, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Webber, William articles, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Weil, Francoise, "Vivant Carion, Pretre Marie et Journaliste,", 1991 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Weissbach, Lee Shai, "The Nature of Philanthropy in Nineteenth-Century France and the Mentalite of the Jewish Elite, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Weissberger, Barbara, "Authors, Characters, and Readers in Grimalte y Gradissa,", circa 1980s (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Wilke, Jurgen articles, 1984-1995 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Williams, Alan review by Jack Censer, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Wills, Antoinette review by Jack Censer, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Wokler, Robert review by Jack Censer, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Woloch, Isser articles, 1986-1987 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Wood, James review by Jack Censer, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Wright, Gordon review by Jack Censer, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Wright, Kent, "Mably's 'Observations sur L'Histoire de France' ,", 1986 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Zagarri, Rosemarie, "The Rights of Man and Woman in Post-Revolutionary America,", 1998 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Zhang, Zhi-lian, "Reform or Revolution,", 1979 (Box 17, Folder 14)
- Series 2: D.C. Sniper research, 2002-2010 (Boxes 17-24)
  This series contains notes, printouts of television transcripts and print coverage, and other research material dating from 2002-2010, collected in the course of Censer's work on his book 'On the Trail of the D.C. Sniper: Fear and the Media' between 2002-2010.
  - Brian Porter dissertation on Montgomery County Schools during sniper attacks, 2010 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Notes on CNN D.C. Sniper coverage of October 3, 2002, mid-2000s (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Notes on D.C. Sniper coverage - October 7, 2002 TV coverage, mid-2000s (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Notes on D.C. Sniper coverage - October 11, 2002 TV coverage, mid-2000s (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Notes on D.C. Sniper coverage - October 14, 2002, mid-2000s (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Notes on D.C. Sniper coverage - October 19-20, 2002, mid-2000s (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Notes on D.C. Sniper coverage - CNN, October 21, 2002, mid-2000s (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Notes on D.C. Sniper coverage - October 23-24, 2002, mid-2000s (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Notes on D.C. Sniper coverage - October 22, 2002, mid-2000s (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Photocopied transcript of 2002 police interview with Lee Boyd Malvo, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Washington Post weekly regional sniper stories, 2002 photocopies, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - D.C. Sniper coverage on highway deaths and TV ratings from 2002, 2004 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Prospectus for "Covering the Killings: The Sniper, Public Opinion, and the Press", circa 2004 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - D.C. Sniper coverage - miscellaneous stories on press from 2002, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - D.C. Sniper coverage notes (labelled emergency messages), mid-2000s (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - D.C. Sniper coverage notes (labelled 'started'), mid-2000s (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - D.C. Sniper coverage notes - attitudes, mid-2000s (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - D.C. Sniper coverage notes - structure, mid-2000s (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - D.C. Sniper coverage notes - police and press, mid-2000s (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - D.C. Sniper coverage notes - leaks, mid-2000s (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - D.C. Sniper book interview questions and printout of news story, 2005 (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - D.C. Sniper coverage notes - fear, mid-2000s (Box 17, Folder 36)
  - D.C. Sniper coverage notes - Camp Rockville, mid-2000s (Box 17, Folder 37)
  - D.C. Sniper coverage notes - other news, mid-2000s (Box 17, Folder 38)
  - D.C. Sniper coverage notes and email - capture, mid-2000s (Box 17, Folder 39)
  - D.C. Sniper book interviews, 2003-2004 (Box 17, Folder 40)
  - Original manuscripts - French Social History, D.C. Sniper book, Washington Post chapter, circa 2000s (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Schools chapter for D.C. Sniper book manuscript, mid-2000s (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - D.C. Sniper continuous coverage chapter manuscript, mid-2000s (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - The News chapter 5 for D.C. Sniper book manuscript, mid-2000s (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - International Press Coverage of D.C. Sniper in 2002, 2004 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Washington Times coverage of D.C. Sniper from 2002, 2003 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - D.C. Sniper book research and notes, mid-2000s (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - D.C. Sniper coverage notes and emails - WTOP, 2005 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - D.C. Sniper coverage notes - WJLA, mid-2000s (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - D.C. Sniper book interview notes from interviews with journalists, mid-2000s (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - D.C. Sniper coverage - interviews with Washington Post journalists, 2004-2005 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - D.C. Sniper coverage notes - miscellaneous interviews, mid-2000s (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - D.C. Sniper coverage notes - Nightline, mid-2000s (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - D.C. Sniper coverage notes - profilers, mid-2000s (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - D.C. Sniper coverage - Richmond Times-Dispatch notes, mid-2000s (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - D.C. Sniper coverage notes, research articles, mid-2000s (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Chicago Sun-Times, San Francisco Chronicle, and Houston Chronicle Sniper coverage from 2002 and notes (1 of 2), 2004 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Chicago Sun-Times, San Francisco Chronicle, and Houston Chronicle Sniper coverage from 2002 and notes (2 of 2), 2004 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Fairfax Journal Sniper news coverage from 2002 and notes, 2003 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Sniper trial/aftermath coverage in D.C. area papers, Chronicle of Higher Education, 2003-2008 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Washington Post Sniper coverage from 2002 and notes, part I (1 of 2), 2003 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Washington Post Sniper coverage from 2002 and notes, part I (2 of 2), 2003 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Notes on new coverage of the D.C. Sniper, Washington Post and Baltimore Sun articles, Montgomery County Public Schools information, 2002-2003 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Washington Post Sniper coverage from 2002, part II (1 of 2), 2003 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Washington Post Sniper coverage from 2002, part II (2 of 2), 2003 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Montgomery County Public Schools information from October 23, 2002, October-November 2002 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Montgomery County Public Schools information, email, 2002-2004 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Fairfax County Public Schools Sniper response, notes, 2002-2003 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Chapters of D.C. Sniper book, mid-2000s (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Chapter 7 of Sniper book, other pages, mid-2000s (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - VHS tapes of Sniper coverage - Nightline, etc., 2002 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Sniper news coverage from 2002 - 60 Minutes II, Newshour with Jim Lehrer, CBS Evening News, Nachman, notes, mid-2000s (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Sniper news coverage from 2002 - Today Show, Hardball, World News Tonight with Peter Jennings, Hannity and Colmes, notes, mid-2000s (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Sniper news coverage from 2002 - Abrams Report, Crossfire, mid-2000s (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Sniper news coverage from 2002 - The O'Reilly Factor, Donahue, Newsnight Aaron Brown, notes, mid-2000s (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Sniper news coverage from 2002 - London Evening Standard, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Montgomery County Public Schools Sniper memos, letters, etc. from 2002, mid-2000s (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Sniper international news coverage from 2002, 2004 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Sniper news coverage from 2002 - Richmond Times-Dispatch (1 of 2), 2003 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Sniper news coverage from 2002 - Richmond Times-Dispatch (2 of 2), 2003 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Sniper News coverage from 2002 - New York Times, 2008 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - D.C. Sniper - Local broaD.C.ast news reports from 2002 and notes, mid-2000s (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - D.C. Sniper research, notes, email correspondence, 2004-2009 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - D.C. Sniper news coverage from 2002 - Nightline and On the Record with Greta Van Sustern, notes, mid-2000s (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - D.C. Sniper coverage - WTOP Collage, 10/3-10/16, 2002, notes, mid-2000s (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - D.C. Sniper coverage notes, interview index, mid-2000s (Box 24, Folder 4)
- Series 3: Teaching, circa 1960s-2003 (Boxes 24-27)
  This series consists largely of syllabi, exam questions, and paper prompts for Jack Censer's graduate and undergraduate classes dating from the 1960s-2003, though mostly from his time as a professor in the history department at George Mason University.
  - New Century College class syllabi, questions, 1997 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - New Century College class exams and questions, circa 1997 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - New Century College class readings, circa 1997 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - New Century College class syllabus, paper assignment, 1997 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Course lecture notes on Early Modern and Modern European History, article reprint, 1989, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Photocopies of notes for Classes, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - History 152 - Cornell summer session, 1996 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - History 100 lectures, email, circa 2001 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - History 100 syllabus, articles, 2002-2003 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - History 100 syllabus and notes, Spring 2002 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Example student notes and syllabus, history 100, Spring 2002 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - History 102 paper instructions and book review suggestions, circa 1980s (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Test taking tips for students, circa 1980s (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Study hints for students at the College of Charleston, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - History 102 exams and syllabi, 1980s (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - History 102, some other courses exams and syllabi, 1960s-1980s (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - History 435 and 102 syllabi and exams, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - History 101 exam questions and syllabi, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Page 230 exams and syllabi, some other classes, circa 1980s (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - History 300 syllabi, circa 1980s (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - History 310 syllabi and exams, circa 1980s (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - History 440 syllabi and exam questions, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - History 441 syllabi and exam questions, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - History 300 syllabus, circa 1980s (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - History 390 syllabi and exam questions, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - History 290 syllabi, student paper bibliographies, 1993 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - History 499 syllabi and guidelines, 1979-1980 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Syllabi for French Revolutionary history courses collected for book lists, 1970s-1980s (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - France and the Arts syllabi, article photocopies, 1980s-1990s (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - France and the Arts syllabi, article photocopies, 1980s-1990s (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - History 535 and 792 syllabi and exam questions, 1987, undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - History 711/731 syllabus, circa 1990s (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Course proposals, exam, bibliographies, 1970s, undated (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Social history materials, 1970s (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Reading list for graduate classes, 1985-1987 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - History 731 class list, syllabus, etc., 1985 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    Restricted (FERPA)
  - History 792 syllabus, readings, 1986 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - History 635, other course materials, circa 1980s (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - History 539 and 639 syllabi and exam questions, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - History 610 readings, circa 1980s (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - History 605 syllabi and handwritten exam questions, circa 1980s (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Western History syllabi from University of Rhode Island (101/102 revision), 1995 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - History 455 syllabus, exam questions, photocopies, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - History 455 notes, readings, exams, circa 1980s (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - "Napoleon: The Man and the Achievement" lecture course, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - French Revolution History 635 readings, syllabus, circa 1980s (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - History 631 syllabus and exam, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - History 711/731 syllabi, class seating, etc., 1992 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - History 635 syllabus, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - History 610 syllabus, circa 1990s (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - History 605 syllabus, readings, exam, circa 1980s (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - History 605 exams, class list, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    Restricted (FERPA, SSNs)
- Series 4: Research, 1968-2006 (Boxes 27-42)
  This series contains material used in Censer's research on the press in 18th century France, as well as various aspects of the French Revolutionary era (mostly photocopies). It also contains multiple versions of some of Censer's scholarly output and related material, including articles, book chapters, essays from his time as a student, publishing logistical materials, reviews, and correspondence. ALso included are materials from Censer's participation in professional organizations such as the American Historical Association.
  - Routledge book proposal, 2002-2003 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Routledge book prospectus, 2002 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Wadsworth publishing, Routledge publishing, 1986-1990 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Articles from the bicentennial year of the French Revolution, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - International roundtable on the press during the revolution, 1988 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - MPG paper (history of advertising), circa 1980s-1990s (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Paper and research on Robespierre as journalist, 1986-1998 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Offprints, reviews, and articles by Censer, 1986-1998 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Botein, Stephen, Jack Censer, and Harriet Ritvo, "The Periodical Press in Eighteenth Century English and French Society,", 1981 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Reviews/articles by Jack Censer, 1979-1989 (Box 28, Folder 5)